William Feng

Fullstack Web Developer

CONTACT INFORMATION

Shenzhen, China williamfeng1001@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/william-feng-736670224

https://williamfeng.herokuapp.com

https://github.com/neatcode-web

SUMMARY

A fullstack web developer who is an expert in professional web applications development with HTML, CSS, React js, Angular, Vue, PHP, C#, Python.

For the past 7 years, have been developing websites, using a keen eye for interactive design to develop pixel-perfect code that translates static design concepts into engaging digital experiences.

Worked on a scrum agile team to build web applications.

Partnering with product managers, designers, and analysts to deeply understand the needs of our users and build a product that serves those needs.

Eager to tackle more complex problems and continue to find ways to maximize user efficiency. The main areas of focus are in HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Javascript, Typescript, React js, Angular, Next js, GraphQL, Material UI, Node js.

SKILLS

- HTML5
- CSS3
- Javascript
- Typescript
- React js
- Angular
- Redux
- Node js
- PHP
- Sass
- GitHub
- Docker

WORK EXPERIENCE

My Tech High, Inc, Remote, United States Fullstack Javascript Developer-Freelancer

01/2021-04/2022

- https://www.mytechhigh.com
- The My Tech High program is possible thanks to forward-thinking school district leaders who recognize the need for choice in education.
- Responsible for developing Nest.js+Apollo Server backend, React frontend app.
- Architectured the gateway+multiple services backend and designed mysgl schemas
- Employed Middleware, typeORM and typescript in nest.js backend.
- Built React+Material UI pages, integrated client app with apollo backend using apollo client.
- TDD (Test Driven Development) with Jest
- Tech stack: Nest.js, Apollo server/client, typeORM, Mysql, React, Typescript, Material UI.

Mangomint, Inc, Remote, United States React Frontend Developer

04/2020-04/2022

- https://www.mangomint.com
- Mangomint is a next-generation software for salons and spas, helping them reduce overhead costs and modernize the client experience.
- Responsible for building responsive ui pages, developing storybook ui components, writing unit test.
- Implemented UI/UX pixel matching, cross-platform responsiveness with Tailwind CSS, Material-UI.
- Develop new user-facing features and maintain existing web-based software applications
- Collaborate with team members and stakeholders to reorganize and update application information architecture
- Contributed to all aspects of the software development lifecycle including design, development, documentation and operations.
- TDD (Test Driven Development) with Jest
- Tech stack: React, Redux, GraphQL, Apollo client/server, Materal UI, Tailwind CSS, Storybook, Jest, Javascript, Typescript, Html, CSS, Sass, MySQL

TOYOTA AUTO BODY CO-OP, Remote, Japan Full Stack Developer

06/2021-03/2022

- https://www.tabco-op.or.jp/ec
- TABC operate shops within Toyota Auto Body Co and main customers are employees and related parties.
- Worked as a remote independent full-stack developer.
- Developed full-stack e-commerce website and its admin system using Laravel 8, Html, Css, jQuery, Mysql, Oracle

• Partnering with product manager and designer to deeply understand the needs of our users and build a product that serves those needs.

Zipline, Remote United States Full stack Developer

01/2019-12/2020

- https://getzipline.com
- Zipline is the only store operations platform built for the realities of day-to-day retail life. Zipline exists to improve the lives of retail workers.
- Worked to add React features on Html, ¡Query website.
- Developed storybook components and built React, Tailwind css UI pages.
- Collaborate closely with the user experience and design team to create and implement user interactions that fit within contemporary design and style guidelines

UltraNote Project, Remote, Sweden Full Stack Javascript Developer

01/2019-09/2019

- https://cloud.ultranote.org
- UltraNote is a Privacy Project which runs on the UltraNote Infinity Privacy Blockchain. UltraNote is Designed to be the ultimate privacy blockchain solution for untraceable & anonymous Payments, Private Messaging, Sharing of Private Documents, Banking and Browsing.
- Worked as a remote independent full-stack developer.
- Developed full-stack web application for cryptocurrency exchange using React, Material UI, Node.js/Express and MongoDB.
- Partnering with product manager and designer to deeply understand the needs of our users and build a product that serves those needs

IT Consultis, Shanghai, China Fullstack Developer

01/2015-12/2018

- ITC empowers the most ambitious global brands through digital transformation on fast moving Asian markets.
- Develop and maintain critical components of eCommerce web application(RWD, PWA) using React.
- Develop and maintain e-commerce applications running on wechat, using Vue(mpVue), React(Taro).
- Communicate with UI/UX designer, PM, DevOps, backend member and develop new projects.
- Provide eCommerce web application architecture solution and building process.
- Communicating and co-working with developers from multiple countries.

Education

Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Kowloon, Hong Kong Bachelor of Science (B.S.) Computer Science 10/2014